export const questions = [
  {
    "question": "",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "1988"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "1978"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "1968"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "1958"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "1968"
  },
  {
    "question": "2. Who was the current Chairman of TATA Group?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Rajesh Gopinathan"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Jamsetji Nusserwanji"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "N Chandrasekaran"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Ratan Tata"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "N Chandrasekaran"
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Who 1s the Founder of TATA Group?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Dorabji Tata"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Jamsetj1 Tata"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Ratan Tata"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "F.C Kohl"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Jamsetj Tata"
  },
  {
    "question": "4. Which of following are TCS Values?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Excellence"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Integrity"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Respect for the Individual"
      },
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Leading Change"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Learning and sharing"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "All are the TCS Values"
  },
  {
    "question": "5. COIN TM Stands for",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Co-Interactive Network"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Co-Inductive Network"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Co-Innovation Network"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Co-Integrated Network"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Co-Innovation Network"
  },
  {
    "question": "0. Which of the following giits are newer appropriate and should",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Gifts in the form of services or other non-cash benefits (e.g. a"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "gifts that are prohibited by the gift givers or recipient s"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "gifts of modest value such as company branded promotional"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "gifts that are prohibited by law"
      },
      {
        "id": "e",
        "text": "gifts of cash or gold or other precious gems"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "a,b.d,e all are the answers"
  },
  {
    "question": "7. Our company has recently announced the launch of an new",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "No"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Tes"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "No"
  },
  {
    "question": "8. Sexual harassment 1s in TCS",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Prohibited"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Discouraged"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Frowned upon"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Prohibited"
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Which are the below stated activates are examples of potential",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "© An employee engages in a business, activity or relationship with"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "An employee undertakes an activity by the interest of our company"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "An employee does anything by which an independent judgment of"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "An employee involving in use of prohibited drugs and substances"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "a,b,c 1s the answers"
  },
  {
    "question": "10. While working on a customer project you receive a call from",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Refrain from sending the requested information"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Send the requested information"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Refrain from sending the requested information"
  },
  {
    "question": "11. Demand for the process and behaviour change in IT",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Arye"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "False"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "12. The following quote was said by computer-to-computer",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Notanand Bennigson"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Sarah Jane Johnston"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Johnston"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "None of them"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Notan and Bennigson"
  },
  {
    "question": "13.Which of the following are considered as IT",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Technical Skills"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Advisory Skills"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Management Skills"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Communication Skills"
      },
      {
        "id": "f",
        "text": "All of them"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "All of them"
  },
  {
    "question": "14. is the field which uses computers and",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "None ofthe above"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "IT Consulting Industry"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Consulting Operations"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "IT Information Security"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "IT Consulting Industry"
  },
  {
    "question": "15. From when the general consulting business evolved to",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "1906"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": ". 1900"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "1990"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "1900"
  },
  {
    "question": "16. TCS had been named as one of the Best Companies to",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "CI"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Working Mother Media and Avatar Group"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "The Cambridge Group"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Working Mother Media and Avatar Group"
  },
  {
    "question": "17. What does Business 4.0 include?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "” Intelligence, Agile, Automated and on the Cloud"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Integrated, Agile, Automated and on the Cloud"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Integrated, Agile, Artificial Intelligence and"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Intelligent, Waterfall, Automated and on the Cloud"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Intelligence, Agile, Automated and on the Cloud"
  },
  {
    "question": "18. Business 4.0 organization works on the approach",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Abundance of Resources & Abundance of talent"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Abundance of Resources & Abundance of Funds"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Abundance of Capital & Abundance of talent"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Abundance of Capital & Abundance of Excellence"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Abundance of Capital & Abundance of talent"
  },
  {
    "question": "19. TCS had been recognised as a prominent",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Global Partner"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Oracle Integrated Cloud Partner"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Technology Partner"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Adobe System Integrator Partner"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Technology Partner"
  },
  {
    "question": "20. When did TCS had been Ranked No 1 in the BT 500",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "2017"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "2015"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "2018"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "2017"
  },
  {
    "question": "21. What are the 4 V’s of big Data?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "None of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Volume, Velocity, Variety, Veracity"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Volume, Viscosity, Variety, Veracity"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Volume, Velocity, Viscosity, Variety"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Volume, Velocity, Variety, Veracity"
  },
  {
    "question": "22. Click Stream Analytics is associated with which",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Volume"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Velocity"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Veracity"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Velocity"
  },
  {
    "question": "23. Name of the intelligent question-answering",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Apache Hadoop"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "IBM BlueMix"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Amazon Dynamo"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "IBM Watson"
  },
  {
    "question": "24. What Big Data open-source software was developed",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Splunk"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Puppet"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Hadoop"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "MongoDB"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Puppet"
  },
  {
    "question": "25. What are the problems associated with Big Data?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "~ All of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Not accustomed to dealing with such large quantities"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Overly complex with relatively slow systems"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Inexperience collecting data from non traditional"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "26. What 1s a best Mobile App when we are dealing with",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Web Application"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Native Application"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Hybrid Application"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Composite Application"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Native Application"
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Recursive Enhancements"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Gradual Enhancements"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Progressive Enhancements"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Progressive Design"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Progressive Enhancements"
  },
  {
    "question": "28. Technique involves fluid layout design so the site",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Adaptive Design"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Responsive Design"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Progressive Design"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Hybrid Design"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Responsive Design"
  },
  {
    "question": "29. Key Expectations in building mobile applications",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Cost effectiveness"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Single Code base"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Option] & 2"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Steady Development"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Option 1 & 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "30. Swipe enabling, Flip features Slide features etc comes",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Application Caching"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Offline database support"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Security"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "None of the above"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "None of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "31. Robots can be used for building houses",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": ".1Tme"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "False"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "32. Which one 1s not one of the Cloud based services",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Public Cloud"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Private Cloud"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Hybrid Cloud"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Enterprise Cloud"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Enterprise Cloud"
  },
  {
    "question": "33. Prime Factors to consider while deciding between",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "All of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Performance Expectations"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Elementary Expense"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "34. Full form of SaaS is",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Service as a Software"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Service as a Support"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Software as a Service"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Software as a Service"
  },
  {
    "question": "35. Which is the Cloud Service where company",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Enterprise Cloud"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Hybrid Cloud"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Private Cloud"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Private Cloud"
  },
  {
    "question": "36. The field that investigates the mechanics of human",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "History"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Psychology"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Sociology"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Cognitive science"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Cognitive science"
  },
  {
    "question": "37. Popular approaches of Artificial Intelligence are",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Computational Intelligence"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "All of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Statistical Methods"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Traditional Symbolic Al"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "38. The Science behind simulating structures inside",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Artificial Intelligence"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Machine Learning"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Robotics"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Neural Networks"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Neural Networks"
  },
  {
    "question": "39. Which of the method is used by Humans while making",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Conscious"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Intuitive bases"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Program based"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Step by step"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Intuitive based"
  },
  {
    "question": "40. The study of computer algorithms that improve",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Machine Learning"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Neural Networks"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Artificial Intelligence"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Robotics"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Machine Learning"
  },
  {
    "question": "41. Which among the following services Apply Al tor",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Send the requested information"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Refrain from sending the requested information"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Refrain from sending the requested information"
  },
  {
    "question": "42. TCS Machine First™ Delivery Model includes",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "” MFDM Execution Model"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "MFDM Collaboration Platform"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "All of them"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "MEDM Maturity Model"
      },
      {
        "id": "e",
        "text": "MFDM Framework"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: -c¢"
  },
  {
    "question": "43. focus on augmenting human contextual",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Inherently"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Business First"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "— Ubiquitous"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Polymorphic"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Business First"
  },
  {
    "question": "44. TCS supports MFDM™ implementation through its",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Enterprise Cloud & Artificial Intelligence"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Enterprisé¢ Intelligent Automation"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Enterprise Intelligent Automation & Artificial Intelligence"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Artificial Intelligence"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Enterprise Intelligent Automation & Artificial"
  },
  {
    "question": "45. Which among the following key for IT Management is",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Embedding security in every system"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Maintaining a focus on customer"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Embracing polymorphic analytics"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Making data ubiquitous"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Embedding security in every system"
  },
  {
    "question": "46. You have developed a new ordering system for your client.",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "You have to check with your supervisor and save the code"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "As you have developed the code, you have full right to save"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "You can get the permission from the client and get the code"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "You should not save the code for reference"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "You should not save the code for reference"
  },
  {
    "question": "477. When Tata Airlines, a division of Tata Sons, is",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "1926"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "1930"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "\"\" +932"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: - 1932"
  },
  {
    "question": "48. Medical Robots can perform Surgical Operations",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "False"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "True"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "49. Artificial Intelligence cannot be used in Health",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "True"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "50. Which 1s India’s first indigenously designed and",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Ambassedor"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Tata Indica"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Tata Nano"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Maruthi 800"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Tata Indica"
  },
  {
    "question": "51. Which characteristics of Big Data deals with Trust",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Veracity"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Volume"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Trust"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Velocity"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Veracity"
  },
  {
    "question": "52. We can use Natural Languages Processing for",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "False"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "True"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "53. How many independently operating companies are",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "89"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Over 100"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Over 100"
  },
  {
    "question": "",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": []
  },
  {
    "question": "54. Which of the methods 1s used by Humans while",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Conscious"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Step by step"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Program based"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Intuitive based"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Intuitive based"
  },
  {
    "question": "55. The change of mindset 1s required — from Optimizing",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Leveraging ecosystems"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Embracing risk"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Mass personalization"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Creating exponential value"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Embracing risk"
  },
  {
    "question": "56. Who is the Founder of TATA group?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "F.C Kohli"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "* Jamsetji"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": ". Dorabji Tata"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Ratan Tata"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Jamsetj1 Tata"
  },
  {
    "question": "577. For organizations that aren’t currently looking to do",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "True"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "False"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "58. What is the change of mindset Business 4.0 is looking at",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Embracing risk and risk mitigation plan"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "None of these"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Utilize abundance of capital & abundance of talent"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Embracing risk and adapt and transform continuously"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Embracing risk and adapt and transform continuously"
  },
  {
    "question": "59. Who formalized the Tata Code of Conduct?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Jamsetj Tata"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Dorabji Tata"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "F.C Kohli"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Ratan Tata"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Ratan Tata"
  },
  {
    "question": "60. The field that investigates the mechanics of human",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Sociology"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Cognitive Science"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Psychology"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "History"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Cognitive Science"
  },
  {
    "question": "61. After the successful completion of a project, the client gifted a",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Inform the supervisor and accept the gift"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Inform Client about our company’s gifts and hospitality policy"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Raise a ethical incident against your client"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Accept the gift"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Inform Client about our company’s gifts and hospitality"
  },
  {
    "question": "62. In the 1990°s which company did TATA Steel acquire?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "ArcelorMittal"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Baosteel"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Posco"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Corus"
  },
  {
    "question": "63. Artificial Intelligence 1s the science and engineering",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "True"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "False"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "64. Which is the old name of TATA MOTORS?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Tata Automobile Enterprise"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Tata'Engineering and Locomotive Company"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Tata Engineering Company"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Tata Locomotive Company"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Tata Engineering and Locomotive Company"
  },
  {
    "question": "65. Machine Perception 1s the ability to use input from",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "True"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "False"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "66. Person who identified the Qualification problem",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Alan Turing"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "John McCarthy"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Ben Brain"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "John McCarthy"
  },
  {
    "question": "67. Big Data Infrastructure can store video files as well",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "False"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "True"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "68. What are 5 TATA Values",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "Integrity,"
  },
  {
    "question": "69. The Science and Technology which deal with Automatic,",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Congnitive Science"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Robotics"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Human Kinematics"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "None of the Above"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Robotics"
  },
  {
    "question": "70. Adopters of Business 4.0 do this by",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Leveraging ecosystems"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "~ Creating exponential values"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "~All of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Mass personalization"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "all of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "71. Some challenges in Artificial Intelligence are",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "All of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Common science"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "~ Technology"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Cost"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "all of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "72. Business 4.0 brings sophistication to the",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Supply chain"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": ". Demand chain"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": ". Demand-Supply"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Demand-Supply"
  },
  {
    "question": "73. When did Tata Motors unveil Tata Nano?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "2008"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "2009"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "2007"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "2010"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "2008"
  },
  {
    "question": "74. What are the 5 TCS Values?",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "Creativity,"
  },
  {
    "question": "75. Big Data Analytics on Genomic Medicine will",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "True"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "False"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "76. World’s biggest source of Big Data",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Oceanic Research"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "‘Space Research"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Traditional Systems"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Mobile Phones"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Space Research"
  },
  {
    "question": "77. According to a study by IBM, approximately how",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "2.7 exabytes"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "27 zetabytes"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "2.7 zetabytes"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "270 petabytes"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: - 2.7 zetabytes"
  },
  {
    "question": "78. 90% of the world’s data was created in the last",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Arye"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "False"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: - True"
  },
  {
    "question": "79. Who formed a joint venture to open Starbucks cafes",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Tata Global Beverages and Starbucks"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "None of those"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Coffee Day Global Limited & Tata Global Beverages"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Starbucks and Cafe Coffee Day"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Tata Global Beverages and Starbucks"
  },
  {
    "question": "80. How many industries do TCS provides its consultancy?",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: 12"
  },
  {
    "question": "81. What 1s the name of the first research center established",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "82. What was TCS’s first onsite project?",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: D"
  },
  {
    "question": "83. TCS is ..... largest IT firm in the world?",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: A"
  },
  {
    "question": "84. Who 1s TCS first General Manager?",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "B"
  },
  {
    "question": "85. TCS provides six major IT services",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: B"
  },
  {
    "question": "86. Which model does TCS follow?",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "Ans: D"
  },
  {
    "question": "87. Tata Consulting Services goes public in India’s",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "C"
  },
  {
    "question": "88. What was originally called the “imitation",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "The Turing test"
  },
  {
    "question": "89. How many independently operating",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "Over 100"
  },
  {
    "question": "90. We use Natural Language Processing for",
    "options": [],
    "correctAnswers": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "97. Which institution was set up in 1936, a pioneer in the",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Indian Institute of Science"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Tata Institute of Social Sciences"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Tata Institute of Fundamental Research"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Tata Management Training Center"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Tata Institute of Social Sciences"
  },
  {
    "question": "98. Which of the 1s not TATA brand?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Voltas"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "~ Tetley"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Westside"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Cafe Coffee Day"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Cafe Coffee Day"
  },
  {
    "question": "99. In which year, Tata Consultancy Services (TCS)",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "2003"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "1995"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "2010"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "2008"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "2003"
  },
  {
    "question": "100. In which year, TCS completed 1ts 50 glorious years?",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "2018"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "2019"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "2020"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "2017"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "2018"
  },
  {
    "question": "101. An international brand acquired by Indian",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Yorkshire Tea"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Lipton"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Tetley group"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Stash Tea"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": []
  },
  {
    "question": "101. An international brand acquired by Indian",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Yorkshire Tea"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Lipton"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Tetley group"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Stash Tea"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Tetley group"
  },
  {
    "question": "102. Which of the following is not part of five core",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Excellence"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Respecting Everyone"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Respect for individual"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Leading change"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Respecting Everyone"
  },
  {
    "question": "103. To which of the following US based motor company,",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Chevrolet"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Ford"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "GMC"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Ford"
  },
  {
    "question": "104. TCS Innovation Labs are providing extended",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Image Processing"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Biometrics"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Analytics"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "All of the above"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "105. Who request the Tata group to manufacture cosmetics",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Jawaharlal Nehru"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Indira Gandhi"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Motilal Nehru"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Morar Desai"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Jawaharlal Nehru"
  },
  {
    "question": "106. Tata Group Companies are spread across",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Communication & ITES"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "~ Manufacturing"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "~ Consumer & Retail"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "All of the above"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "All of the above"
  },
  {
    "question": "107. In which year Vistara takes to the skies &",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "1990"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "2005"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "2010"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": ".\"2015"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "2015"
  },
  {
    "question": "108. Which Tata Company becomes the first listed Indian",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Tata Chemicals"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Tata Communications"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Tata Investment Corporation"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Tata Consultancy Service"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Tata Consultancy Service"
  },
  {
    "question": "109. What is the critical mission of Tata group that 1s at the",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Corporate Social Responsibility (CSR)"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "Brand Equity & Business Promotion (BEBP)"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Tata Code of Conduct (TCoC)"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "Tata Business Excellence Model (TBEM)"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Corporate Social Responsibility"
  },
  {
    "question": "110. India’s best-known Cancer Hospital and Research Center",
    "options": [
      {
        "id": "a",
        "text": "Tata Memorial Hospital"
      },
      {
        "id": "b",
        "text": "JRD Tata Eco-technology Center"
      },
      {
        "id": "c",
        "text": "Both of the above options"
      },
      {
        "id": "d",
        "text": "None of the above"
      }
    ],
    "correctAnswers": "Tata Memorial Hospital"
  }
];